<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>New Jersey Real Estate Podcast with Brett Sikora</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Sikora Group - your professional New Jersey Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Brett Sikora</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-11-23 12:22:15 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Brett Sikora</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>brett@sellwithsikora.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Brett Sikora</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the North Jersey Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Sikora Group - your professional New Jersey Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Led Us to Switch to eXp Realty?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-led-us-to-switch-to-exp-realty.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-28 09:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2019/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Why+We+Made+the+Switch+to+eXp+Realty.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’ve made the switch to eXp Realty, but what about it drew us in? 

As a cloud-based, agent-owned brokerage, eXp utilizes leading-edge technology that facilitates our ability to provide the best service possible to our clients. 

One reason for our switch is their second-to-none training. Through the cloud-based system, we have 24 to 30 hours’ worth of live training for our agents each week, and it’s provided by some of the top agents in the world. 

“With eXp, we’ll be able to utilize leading-edge technology to provide the best service possible to our clients.”

The collaborative nature to eXp’s approach is another reason for our switch. The agents are all aligned and working in concert to achieve goals. If we want to learn how we can set a new mark for home sales in a given year, it’s not coming from the local manager or the brokers. Instead, we’re learning from agents that have hit that mark before.

If you have any questions about our switch or anything else related to real estate, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to working with you at eXp!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2019/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Why+We+Made+the+Switch+to+eXp+Realty.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2019/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Why+We+Made+the+Switch+to+eXp+Realty.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’ve transitioned over to eXp Realty? Why, you ask? Find out in today’s message.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’ve transitioned over to eXp Realty? Why, you ask? Find out in today’s message.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Let Asbestos Go Unabated in Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-let-asbestos-go-unabated-in-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-28 09:57:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Important+Safety+Tips+Regarding+Asbestos.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m joined once again by home inspector Chris Burrows, and this time we’re talking about where you can find asbestos in your home.

There are two main areas where asbestos is commonly found: in floor tiles or around old basement boilers with insulated pipes.

In the latter case, these types of pipes are usually wrapped in friable material, which can become airborne quickly and can contain up to 60% asbestos. At the 0:33 mark in the video above, I’ve included a picture of what this looks like. It’s pretty easy to identify, especially if you live in an older home.

“Asbestos that’s intact (i.e., not coming apart) is less of a concern unless it’s friable material, which can break apart.”

The fiber count of asbestos found in floor tiles is usually 2% to 10% lower than found in wrapped pipes. Asbestos that’s intact (i.e., not coming apart) is less of a concern unless it’s friable material, which can break apart. In either case, it’s important that you test these areas to see if you need to perform an asbestos abatement.

If you have any more asbestos questions for Chris, you can call his office at (201) 840-6126 or visit his website www.cmburrowsinc.com.

As always, if you have any real estate questions, feel free to call or email me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Important+Safety+Tips+Regarding+Asbestos.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Important+Safety+Tips+Regarding+Asbestos.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Asbestos can accumulate in two areas of a home: in floor tiles and around old basement boilers with insulated pipes.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Asbestos can accumulate in two areas of a home: in floor tiles and around old basement boilers with insulated pipes.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Step-by-Step Explanation of the Mold Inspection Process</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-step-by-step-explanation-of-the-mold-inspection-process.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-28 09:09:09 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+How+the+Mold+Inspection+Process+Works.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Chris says when he first receives a call, the symptoms are often described as a musty smell or a leak from the roof or roof deck. The first test he’ll conduct is what’s called the “air cassette test.” This test will draw in samples of the air to test its quality for any form of mold that can be a health hazard.

The litmus test that Chris uses to determine whether or not there are dangerous levels of mold within the home is measuring the inside air against the air outdoors. Outside air will always contain mold, and should, therefore, be at higher levels than what’s inside the home. That will signal to Chris just how safe or poor the air quality is in the home—especially in the bedrooms and living space.  

“Outside air will always contain mold, and should, therefore, be at higher levels than what’s inside the home.”

Once that’s done, Chris will extract and inspect a physical sample from Sheetrock in the home. He swabs the Sheetrock to determine the type of mold and its effects.

He’ll then use a strip of tape, for what is called a “tape lift,” to seal the mold down onto the Sheetrock, and it’ll be sent off to the lab for further analysis.

Beyond that, Chris will conduct a visual assessment of the property as well.

If you notice a musty smell or you’ve experienced water damage in your home, Chris is a great source to call upon to protect against the toxic effects of mold. Reach out and get in touch with him.

For any other real estate-related questions or concerns, be sure to get in touch with me as well. I’d be happy to assist you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+How+the+Mold+Inspection+Process+Works.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+How+the+Mold+Inspection+Process+Works.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m joined by Chris Burrows, a home inspector who has long-served our area, to discuss mold in the home and how he tests for its presence.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m joined by Chris Burrows, a home inspector who has long-served our area, to discuss mold in the home and how he tests for its presence.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>An Example of a Tool We Use to Serve Your Real Estate Needs</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-example-of-a-tool-we-use-to-serve-your-real-estate-needs.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-17 11:54:03 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+An+Example+of+the+Tools+We+Use+to+Serve+Your+Real+Estate+Needs.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There is a behind-the-scenes soldier that does a lot of work for us here at the Sikora Group that I’d like to highlight today: our all-in-one letter folder, envelope stuffer, and envelope sealer.

This machine allows us to produce up to 1,300 envelopes in an hour. If a buyer wants a property in a specific neighborhood and wants us to map out that whole area, we can then go into the tax records, pull out everyone’s address, upload them into our machine, and then print all their names on the envelopes and folders. After that, we tuck our mailers in one of the machine’s slots, and the machine stuffs and seals the envelopes. All we then have to do is stamp and send  them out.

“This machine allows us to produce up to 1,300 envelopes in an hour.”

This tool is just another part of our arsenal to make sure that we help our buyers and sellers from every angle; with it, we can reach people when doing so by phone isn’t an option, and it’s also useful for blanket mailings. It benefits both buyers looking for off-market properties and also our sellers looking to announce open houses.

If you have any questions about the ways that we help our buyers and sellers or about real estate in general, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d be glad to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+An+Example+of+the+Tools+We+Use+to+Serve+Your+Real+Estate+Needs.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+An+Example+of+the+Tools+We+Use+to+Serve+Your+Real+Estate+Needs.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’ll discuss one of the many tools we use to sell more homes and find more properties for buyers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’ll discuss one of the many tools we use to sell more homes and find more properties for buyers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Does the Mold Removal Process Look Like?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-does-the-mold-removal-process-look-like.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-30 09:55:11 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+to+Do+If+You+Find+Mold+in+Your+Property.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Mold is never a welcome sight for homeowners, but fortunately, taking care of this problem before it becomes a bigger problem isn’t difficult.

To show you what the mold removal process entails, I’ve brought in Justin Guyre of Renew Restoration, and I’m using the house my wife and I are currently building as an example.

We recently had a water leak between the second and third floors of the unit, and we called Justin and his team to test for mold. Once the results came back positive, they got started on the remediation process.

If you find mold in your home, the first thing you should do is identify the source of it, whether it’s from relative humidity or direct water contact. Mold can’t grow without water, so once the source is identified, you can get to work on removing it.

Removal experts like Justin rely heavily on the data they find when performing their tests because there are many different species of mold and not all of them are harmful. The species that grow on building materials and are water damage indicators, however, must be removed.

“Mold can’t grow without water, so once the source is identified, you can get to work on removing it.”

In our case, they identified the species of mold that was present, where the water leak was coming from and proceeded to remove as much of the affected material as they could that wasn’t structural. After that, they disinfected the parts of the structure that were impacted and set up proper air scrubbing so they could clean the air.

Once that was done, they post-tested the environment to check that the area was back to a “Condition 1” state. After we close the walls and finish the home, we’ll test the air one more time before we move in to ensure everything is safe.

If you understand what’s causing mold in your home, there are many cost-effective things you can do yourself to fix it and prevent it from happening again. Proper dehumidification is very important in areas like your basement, so keep your humidity levels below 65% all year long. If you let it rise above 65% for an extended period of time, don’t be surprised to open up a closet door one day and find mold growing.

In a situation like that, where there’s no direct water contact, you might not need a total mold removal—you might just need to remove the spores. In other situations, such as when mold grows on your home’s sheetrock from direct water contact, you’ll have to remove the sheetrock entirely instead of just cleaning it.

Why? According to Justin, the molds that grow this way typically have hyphae, or the root system of their vegetative growth. You have to remove the sheetrock entirely to make sure that you can kill that root system and clean any mold that’s spread to the structure of the house, itself. By HEPA vacuuming and air scrubbing, this issue can be fixed without doing a tremendous amount of extra work.

If you have any more questions about mold removal, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+to+Do+If+You+Find+Mold+in+Your+Property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+to+Do+If+You+Find+Mold+in+Your+Property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’ll show you what the mold removal process looks like so you know what to expect if you ever find mold in your home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’ll show you what the mold removal process looks like so you know what to expect if you ever find mold in your home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Difference Between a Short Sale and a Foreclosure</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-difference-between-a-short-sale-and-a-foreclosure.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-16 09:38:28 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+The+Difference+Between+a+Short+Sale+and+a+Foreclosure.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I often get questions about what short sales and foreclosures are, as well as which one is best for buyers. Today we’ll be going over what the key differences between them are.

To illustrate a short sale, let’s say a seller owes $500,000 on their property’s mortgage but wants to sell it for $400,000. The bank will take a hit of $100,000 if they agree to do so. The problem is that short sale properties can take a long time (six to 12 months) to sell. If it’s taking too long, the bank could change their mind and request more from the seller. It could turn out to be a waste of your time if the bank ultimately decides to sell to a new lender and they then foreclose the home. If you get involved in a short sale, make sure it’s good and that you’re able to wait awhile.

“Between a foreclosure and a short sale, we’ve found you’ll often get a better price on foreclosures.”

On the other hand, foreclosures are already owned and have regular transaction times. You could close in 15 to 30 days, get a mortgage, and treat the process as you would when buying a regular home. Most foreclosures are sold as-is, so you won’t find sellers willing to make many repairs. Between a foreclosure and a short sale, we’ve found you’ll often get a better price on foreclosures. Unfortunately, we don’t see many foreclosures come on the market, and the ones that do are often purchased quickly by investors.

While we prefer the pursuit of foreclosures, we can still help you with any short sales you may be interested in. Feel free to reach out to us if you have any questions or need more information. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+The+Difference+Between+a+Short+Sale+and+a+Foreclosure.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+The+Difference+Between+a+Short+Sale+and+a+Foreclosure.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Short sales may be a long process, but foreclosures are harder to obtain. Here are some differences between the two.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Short sales may be a long process, but foreclosures are harder to obtain. Here are some differences between the two.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Market Shift Is Here and Your Equity Could Be at Risk</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-market-shift-is-here-and-your-equity-could-be-at-risk.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-30 14:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Sellers+Can+Expect+From+the+2018+Fall+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s been happening with our Jersey City/Hoboken area market so far in 2018? How should sellers feel about our fall market moving forward? Let’s look at the latest year-to-date statistics and how they compare to the same numbers from 2017.

The number of new listings in Jersey City increased 35% from 798 to 1,216 homes on the market. There are more homes for buyers to choose from, and this increase has created a healthier market in downtown Jersey City. The number of sales, meanwhile, decreased from 477 to 402. That’s not a huge change, but keep in mind that we have a lot of new construction inventory that’s not showing up on the MLS. Sales are still out there and buyers are still buying—you just need to give them a reason to buy.

“Sales are still out there, and buyers are still buying—you just need to give them a reason to buy.”

In Hoboken, the number of new listings increased 22% from 1,139 to 1,460 homes on the market. Unlike Jersey City, though, the number of sales in this area increased slightly from 688 to 705.

This data tells us that a shift is happening in our market, but I don’t think home values are going to dip because the banking industry is still very strong. If you’ve been on the fence about selling, I recommend that you do it now.

On that note, we’re confident that our marketing strategies can help you get your home sold for top dollar, so if you would like to get started now, don’t hesitate to reach out to us.

If you have any further questions about our fall market, feel free to give us a call or send us an email as well. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Sellers+Can+Expect+From+the+2018+Fall+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Sellers+Can+Expect+From+the+2018+Fall+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Inventory is growing in our market, but you shouldn’t expect home values to dip. If you’re a seller, I suggest you put your home on the market now.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Inventory is growing in our market, but you shouldn’t expect home values to dip. If you’re a seller, I suggest you put your home on the market now.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Ask an Agent Before You Hire Them?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-should-you-ask-agent-before-you.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-25 16:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+to+Ask+Your+Agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking to hire an agent to help you purchase a new home, ask these three questions to ensure they’re the right pick for you.


Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.


There are three things that you should ask a potential buyer’s agent before you decide to work with them. This is especially true since we’ve reached the hot, competitive spring market.

1. “How many homes did you sell in the last 12 months?” The national average, according to the National Association of Realtors, is four or five homes in 12 months. We’re seeing agents out there that are doing 100 or more transactions, but even if the agent is doing 24 or 25, it’s a healthy balance that indicates they know what they’re doing.

“An agent’s last three clients can let you know how their processes went and whether or not they had a good experience.”

2. “Can I reach out to your last three clients?” Ask if you can reach out to the last three buyers they helped purchase a home. Those people can let you know how their processes went and whether or not they had a good experience. Did they trust the agent?

3. “What strategy will you use to get me into the home?” What are they doing to inform you about the market? In areas like Hoboken, Jersey City, Chatham, and Summit, we’re seeing a lot of bidding wars. They’re not as common as they were in the past, but you definitely want to make sure that your agent is going to put their best foot forward in order to ensure that you get the property you desire for the price you want and in the time frame you want it.

If you have any questions for me about buying a home or hiring an agent, please feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+to+Ask+Your+Agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+to+Ask+Your+Agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re looking to hire an agent to help you purchase a new home, ask these three questions to ensure they’re the right pick for you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re looking to hire an agent to help you purchase a new home, ask these three questions to ensure they’re the right pick for you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Different Loan Products for Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-different-loan-products-for-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2018-03-19 16:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Loan+Types.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a homebuyer, you should know what your options are when it comes to financing your purchase. I’ll go over four different types of loans for you today.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

There are a number of different loan products that you can use to purchase your home. I’ll go over four of them today.

The first and most popular loan is conventional financing backed by Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac. This loan requires 5%, 10%, 15%, or 20% down, and you can use this option on a condo or single-family home.

The second is FHA financing. An FHA loan lets you move into a home with as little as 3.5% down. The private mortgage insurance rate does end up being a bit higher, but the FHA loan also works well with a lower credit score.

“An FHA loan lets you move into a home with as little as 3.5% down.”

The 203k loan is similar to the FHA loan but it allows you to rehab the property. The 203k program gives you money to make upgrades and renovate the home. Of course, they are going to come in and monitor the work to make sure that it’s done by a qualified contractor. Still, that’s a great product if you want to renovate a bank-owned or short sale property.

The final product is the homestyle loan. This is similar to the 203k loan but you do have to put a bit more money down than you would for an FHA. You can’t use the FHA or 203k on a condo, but you can use a homestyle loan. The homestyle loan will also finance construction costs. Again, they will monitor your process to make sure you are working with a qualified contractor. This is a great product to use.

If you have any other questions about buying a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Loan+Types.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/Videos+/2018/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Loan+Types.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

As a homebuyer, you should know what your options are when it comes to financing your purchase. I’ll go over four different types of loans for you today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

As a homebuyer, you should know what your options are when it comes to financing your purchase. I’ll go over four different types of loans for you today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Whats Happening So Far in the Spring Real Estate Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-happening-so-far-in-spring-real.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2018-02-09 11:32:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Whats+Happening+So+Far+in+the+Spring+Real+Estate+Market%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What should you expect from the 2018 spring real estate market? I have some good tips on what to keep an eye out for.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

What’s going on in the spring market of 2018?

One thing that I’ve been seeing quite a bit lately is that for multi-family owners, the numbers have changed significantly since last year.

Another thing is that if you’re looking to purchase a home and you need to sell your current home first in order to do so, keep in mind that it’s still a seller’s market, so you should be able to find a buyer easily.

On the buyer’s side of things, you’ll definitely need to be as aggressive as possible. You’ll probably need to have your current home under contract before you buy a new one. Fortunately, since it’s a seller’s market, you can dictate exactly what’s going on in that transaction. A lot of times, the buyers that are purchasing the homes you’re selling don’t need to be in there at a certain time; they’re usually month-to-month rentals, they might have a lease ending, or they’re staying at home.

“When it comes to putting offers on properties, I always say to come in strong.”

We can start with a contract and include a clause that says the purchase of the home is contingent on your finding your home in a certain period of time. You can also get a leaseback contingency, where you have 60 days to occupy the home post-closing.

When it comes to putting offers on properties, I always say to come in strong. If there are multiple offers on the home, you’ll need a strong number to be accepted by the seller. We hate to see a tough negotiation in which the price is driven down quite a bit, but then a second offer comes in and starts to look much better to the seller.

If you have any questions about the spring market or buying and selling a home, please feel free to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Whats+Happening+So+Far+in+the+Spring+Real+Estate+Market%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Whats+Happening+So+Far+in+the+Spring+Real+Estate+Market%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

What should you expect from the 2018 spring real estate market? I have some good tips on what to keep an eye out for.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

What should you expect from the 2018 spring real estate market? I have some good tips on what to keep an eye out for.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Mistakes Investors Should Avoid When Renovating a Property </title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-mistakes-investors-should-avoid-when.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-22 12:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Mistakes+Investors+Should+Avoid+When+Renovating+a+Property.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are five things investors don’t count on when renovating a property that I want you to know today.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

There are five things that investors don’t plan on when it comes to renovating a property:

1. Having enough money. Doing a project like this certainly takes a lot of money. If you don’t have enough money on hand, you will have to take out a lot of loans, which will cost you more interest-wise and cut down on your profits.

2. Not planning enough time. Stripping everything out of the house, framing, installing electrical and plumbing—it takes a long time to get all of this done.

3. Not having enough skill. We have a number of contractors, plumbers, and electricians in the area. Some of them are great, and some of them are not so good. Some of these builders are doing their own work on their properties as well, so they can move things along and they know what’s happening in the process.

“It takes time to find a good deal on a property.”

4. Not enough knowledge of the local area. There are a lot of investors coming into the market who may not know the ins and outs of our area.

5. Not having enough patience. It takes time to find deals that make sense. People watch all these flipping shows on TV and then rush into a deal that doesn’t necessarily make sense just to get their first property.

Keep these things in mind when renovating your investment property. If you have any other questions about real estate, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Mistakes+Investors+Should+Avoid+When+Renovating+a+Property.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Mistakes+Investors+Should+Avoid+When+Renovating+a+Property.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are five things investors don’t count on when renovating a property that I want you to know today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are five things investors don’t count on when renovating a property that I want you to know today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Looking Back on 2017 and Forward to 2018 </title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/looking-back-on-2017-and-forward-to-2018.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-28 13:12:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Looking+Back+on+2017+and+Forward+to+2018.mp4</guid>
        <description>

2017 was a great year for the world of real estate. Will 2018 be another great year, or will home values start to level off?

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

What happened in the 2017 real estate market, and what can you expect from the 2018 market?

Overall, 2017 was a very good year in the world of real estate, especially in New Jersey. We had bidding wars out in Sussex County, and Weehawken in Hudson County broke the record for most appreciation. There were bidding wars in Monmouth County, and houses were flying off the shelves in Morris County.

2017 was a very strong year for appreciation, as we saw 7%, 10%, and 14% appreciation in just 12 months.

“There is still a ton of consumer confidence in the real estate market.”

So, what will happen in 2018? Is the market going to cool off? At some point, it needs to stop, right?

I don’t know exactly where prices will land in 2018, but there is still a ton of consumer confidence out there. Buyers are out looking at homes left and right, and the market is very busy. Even though we’re in the holiday season, people are still out and about.

I don’t see our market slowing down too much as we head into the spring market. Inventory is still low, and people are getting ready to list their homes this spring. We could see another climb in home values through the spring market with all of those buyers still out there.

If you have any other questions about our real estate market, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Looking+Back+on+2017+and+Forward+to+2018.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Looking+Back+on+2017+and+Forward+to+2018.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

2017 was a great year for the world of real estate. Will 2018 be another great year, or will home values start to level off?

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

2017 was a great year for the world of real estate. Will 2018 be another great year, or will home values start to level off?

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Demands Every Homebuyer Should Make of Their Agent</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-demands-every-homebuyer-or-seller.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-12-11 13:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+4+Demands+Every+Homebuyer+or+Seller+Should+Make.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are a few things you need to ensure that your agent does for you. Here are four of the most important.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

When you are buying a home, there are four things you should absolutely demand of your agent:

1. Tell the truth about pricing. Many agents will tell you that it’s fine to lowball a seller, but most times it ends up with you either paying more for the property or losing it altogether. They should understand the market and know what a strong offer looks like and be confident enough to convey the importance of making one.

2. Understand the timetable your family is dealing with. If you need to close quickly, your agent needs to understand that. A good agent should be able to adapt to your timeline, rather than the other way around.

“Don’t rush the home buying process.”

3. Remove as many of the challenges as possible. Appraisal and home inspection issues aren’t uncommon, so knowing how to negotiate those things and get to the closing table is huge.

4. Find the right house. Don’t rush it. I see clients all the time feeling like they need to buy or need to get into a home. Your agent should not be pushing you to make a purchase if you aren’t ready. It’s best to take your time because this is a huge decision.

If you have any questions about why these demands are important or want to know how we help our buyers in the home search process, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+4+Demands+Every+Homebuyer+or+Seller+Should+Make.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+4+Demands+Every+Homebuyer+or+Seller+Should+Make.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

There are a few things you need to ensure that your agent does for you. Here are four of the most important.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

There are a few things you need to ensure that your agent does for you. Here are four of the most important.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Steps Do You Need to Take to Buy a Home in 2018?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-steps-do-you-need-to-take-to-buy.html</link>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-13 13:08:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Steps+Do+You+Need+to+Take+to+Buy+a+Home+in+2018%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

In order to purchase a home in 2018 and take advantage of the spring market, there are eight steps you need to take now.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

If you’re thinking about buying a home in 2018, now is the time to get your ducks in a row so you can take advantage of the spring market once it hits. There are eight steps you need to take to prepare yourself:


  
    Check your credit score. We have lenders who can help you, and there are also many online credit companies that can guide you.
  
  
    Don’t open any new credit cards or lines of credit.
  
  
    Source your down payment and check with your Realtor or a lender before depositing a big chunk of money into your bank account.
  
  
    Start interviewing real estate agents. Not every Realtor is alike. There are a lot who do a lot of business and lot who only do a little business, so make sure you’re set up with the right one so you don’t end up in a bad situation halfway through the transaction.
  


“Taking these steps will have you prepared to buy the home you want in 2018.”


  
    Keep tabs on interest rates. Sometimes they’re high and sometimes they’re low, but they have been hovering right around that 4% mark.
  
  
    Find a mortgage lender. We can help refer you to certain people we know and trust and who are local and in tune with our market.
  
  
    Get pre-approved. This is an important start to the whole process and it will let you know where you stand as far as what you can purchase and what your payments will be.
  
  
    Start viewing properties. It can take as long as three or four months to find the right property. Once we find a property for our clients, it takes an average of 45 to 60 days to get to closing, so keep that in mind.
  


If you want to close on a home in May or June, you need to take some of these steps and get some of this stuff out of the way so you’ll be right on track when your lease is up or you’re ready to put your current home on the market.

If you have any more questions about buying a home in 2018 or you’re curious about our North Jersey real estate market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Steps+Do+You+Need+to+Take+to+Buy+a+Home+in+2018%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Steps+Do+You+Need+to+Take+to+Buy+a+Home+in+2018%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

In order to purchase a home in 2018 and take advantage of the spring market, there are eight steps you need to take now.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

In order to purchase a home in 2018 and take advantage of the spring market, there are eight steps you need to take now.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Costs That Shock First-Time Homebuyers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-costs-that-shock-first-time-homebuyers.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-10-03 10:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Costs+That+Shock+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Your mortgage isn’t the only thing you’ll have to pay when you buy a home. Here are five unexpected costs.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

If you’re thinking about buying a home, you need to be aware of all of the costs associated before you decide to take the leap. Here are five expenses that typically shock and/or creep up on first-time buyers.

1. Closing costs. These include mortgage taxes, lender application fees, attorney fees, and more. They vary from state to state and lending company to lending company, so make sure you get an accurate estimate of what yours will be.

2. Home improvements. According to a study by the Harvard University Joint Center on housing studies, the average home maintenance is 1% to 2% of the value of the home per year. For a $300,000 home, that’s around $3,000 per year. A condo will have slightly lower maintenance costs.

3. Property taxes. They vary from town to town and tend to go up most years. However, if you feel like what you’re paying is too high, you can appeal your property taxes on your own or with the help of an attorney.

“Closing costs vary from state to state.”

4. Utilities. These also vary based on the climate and the city you’re living in. In Atlanta, utilities are around $2,600 per year. In Portland, they are closer to $3,800.

5. Homeowners insurance. If you’re getting a mortgage, you’re going to be required to have homeowners insurance regardless. The annual premium is around $1,132 per year.

If you have any questions for us about any of these costs or anything else relating to real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Costs+That+Shock+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Costs+That+Shock+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Your mortgage isn’t the only thing you’ll have to pay when you buy a home. Here are five unexpected costs.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Your mortgage isn’t the only thing you’ll have to pay when you buy a home. Here are five unexpected costs.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Questions to Ask Before Looking at Homes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-questions-to-ask-before-looking-at.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-18 11:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Questions+to+Ask+Before+Looking+at+Homes.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The first step in buying a home isn’t looking online for properties. It’s answering these five questions about your financial situation.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

If you’re thinking about buying a home, here are five questions that you should ask yourself before you even start the first step of the process:

1. Do you have a steady source of income? If you’ve been employed on a regular basis with a steady level of income, that’s a good start.

2. Do you have a good record of paying bills? This will affect your credit and will also tell a lender whether you’re responsible enough to handle a mortgage payment.

3. Do you have enough money for a down payment? You only need 3.5% with an FHA loan, but a majority of people put down 20% to avoid paying private mortgage insurance.

“A steady source of income is essential.”

4. Do you have any outstanding debts? Any kind of monthly payment you have could affect your debt-to-income ratio.

5. Can you pay the mortgage each month with additional costs? When you pay rent, that’s typically all the money you have to worry about (save utilities and cable). When you own a home, there are a lot of extra costs that come up. Whether you have to replace an appliance or fix a hole in the wall, you’ll need to have enough money to do that.

If you can answer yes to all of these questions, it might be time to give us a call and get a buyer consultation set up. Then we can get you pre-approved with our preferred lender and begin your search.

If you have any questions, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Questions+to+Ask+Before+Looking+at+Homes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+5+Questions+to+Ask+Before+Looking+at+Homes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

The first step in buying a home isn’t looking online for properties. It’s answering these five questions about your financial situation.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

The first step in buying a home isn’t looking online for properties. It’s answering these five questions about your financial situation.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Should You Think About Before You Sell?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-should-you-think-about-before-you.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-17 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Should+You+Think+About+Before+You+Sell%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re a seller, what are a some ways you can maximize your opportunity? Today, I’ve got two methods to share.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

How can you maximize your opportunity as a seller?

Today, I’ve got a few tips to share on how to do just that.

First of all, remember to schedule around holidays. Avoid timing sales within the two weeks prior to a holiday or within the last two weeks of August.

Inventory and conditions overall will tend to pick up outside of those times.

“Don’t miss out by waiting for the next best thing.”

Next, try not to be overly selective about offers. In today’s economy, getting an offer in general is a win. You don’t want to pass over a good thing in the hope that something even better will come along.

Don’t let yourself miss out by waiting for the next best thing.

Accepting offers, even ones that are lower, doesn’t mean you have to stop showing the property until you’re under contract.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Should+You+Think+About+Before+You+Sell%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+What+Should+You+Think+About+Before+You+Sell%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re a seller, what are a some ways you can maximize your opportunity? Today, I’ve got two methods to share.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re a seller, what are a some ways you can maximize your opportunity? Today, I’ve got two methods to share.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Need to Start With a Strong Offer</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-need-to-start-with-strong-offer.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-03 11:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Why+You+Need+to+Start+With+a+Strong+Offer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When you make your first offer on a home, it needs to be a strong one. There are a couple of main reasons why.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

When you make your first offer on a home, you need to make sure that it’s a strong offer. Why?

First of all, there’s the matter of etiquette to the seller.

For example, let’s say that a seller lists their property at $800,000. It just hit the market and you see it over the weekend for the first time. You make an offer at $750,000.

Now, the seller hasn’t been on the market long enough to accept that offer. They might counter offer and they may even accept your offer at $760,000. However, they will continue to show that property to other buyers. They will also look for every chance to kill that deal.

“Don’t give someone else the chance to make a better offer than yours.”

The other thing to keep in mind is that once another buyer knows that you’ve already made an offer on the property, they will go in with a stronger offer than yours. Don’t give another buyer a chance to steal your dream home away.

Go in with a strong offer, get in and out of attorney review, and try to get to the closing table as soon as possible.

If you have any other questions about buying a home in today’s market, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Why+You+Need+to+Start+With+a+Strong+Offer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+Why+You+Need+to+Start+With+a+Strong+Offer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When you make your first offer on a home, it needs to be a strong one. There are a couple of main reasons why.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When you make your first offer on a home, it needs to be a strong one. There are a couple of main reasons why.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Home Ready for the Spring Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-your-home-ready-for-spring-market.html</link>
        
          <category>North Jersey Real Estate Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-27 14:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+3+tips+to+prepare+for+the+spring+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Is your home ready for the spring selling season? If not, here are three simple things you can do now to make your home more appealing to buyers.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

The spring market is just around the corner, and there are three simple things that you can do to prepare your home to sell for top dollar:

1. Deep clean your home. Hire a professional cleaning crew and have them clean the windows and regrout the tubs. People do not like to see the mildew in the bathroom, so this is an easy way to make your home more appealing to buyers.

2. Get rid of all clutter and personal items. Put things in storage or in cabinets. No matter what, make sure your countertops are clean and take all of the magnets off of the fridge.

3. Add a fresh coat of paint. Choose a neutral color, like a nice, basic gray. That will go a long way to make your home look fantastic.

“Hire a professional cleaning crew to make your home sparkle.”

If you have any other questions about the spring market or the home selling process, give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+3+tips+to+prepare+for+the+spring+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Brett+Sikora/North+Jersey+Real+Estate-+3+tips+to+prepare+for+the+spring+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Is your home ready for the spring selling season? If not, here are three simple things you can do now to make your home more appealing to buyers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Is your home ready for the spring selling season? If not, here are three simple things you can do now to make your home more appealing to buyers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2 Ways to Calculate Your Investment Return</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2-ways-to-calculate-your-investment.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate Investment</category>
        
        <author>Brett Sikora</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-14 10:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

How can you figure out your investment return on your rental property? I’ll go over two ways to do that today.

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report.
Want to buy a home? Search all homes for sale.

How can you calculate what your return will be on an investment? There are actually two ways.

“There are two ways to calculate your investment return depending on whether you used cash or financed the purchase.”

The first way to calculate your return is by figuring out the cap rate. With cap rate, you’re basically going to take your net profit of rental income after taxes and expenses and divide it by the property value. For example, if you are bringing in $10,000 a year on a home you paid $100,000 cash for, your cap rate is 10%.

$10,000 (net rent) / $100,000 (purchase price) = .10 (multiplied by 100 is 10%)

The other way is to figure out your cash-on-cash return. If you’re using a mortgage, you’ll put less money down and will be leveraging the bank’s money, so, you’d take that $10,000 net profit and subtract the debt service. If you spent $20,000 out of pocket to purchase that $100,000 home and the debt service was say, $5,000, your return would be 25%.

$10,000 (net rent) - $5,000 (debt service) = $5,000
$5,000 / $20,000 (down payment with a mortgage) = 0.25 (multiplied by 100 is 25%)

If you have any questions on this topic or if you have any other questions about real estate, please don’t hesitate to reach out. I look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

How can you figure out your investment return on your rental property? I’ll go over two ways to do that today.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Brett Sikora</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

How can you figure out your investment return on your rental property? I’ll go over two ways to do that today.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in New Jersey, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Brett Sikora</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Brett Sikora</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Sikora Group - your professional New Jersey Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
